Daniel Cox

Dartmouth, NS, Canada Phone: (902) 818 – 8129

Email: danielcox996@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/daniel-cox-b0320115b Website: https://dangerousdaniel.github.io/

ABOUT

I graduated from NSCC IT Programming (Class of 2020). For the last 2 years I've been developing a 2D fantasy platform game named Vex Monsters, where you save monsters from an evil mysterious villain.

Throughout my experience as a programmer, I have completed several challenging projects. These projects taught me a hands-on mindset and approach. I learned how to analyze, study, and apply learning to figure out solutions when working alone or with a team.

SUMMARY

Reliable, organized team player with good leadership and tutoring skills

OBJECTIVE

Finding a job in IT as a game development, software developer or computer technician.

SKILLS

Unity, C#, Creative Writing, Project Management, Computer Maintenance, Software Installation, Computer Hardware, Responsive Web Design, Game Development, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), Video Editing

TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

C++, Python, Java, PHP, HTML, CSS, Windows, GitHub, Laravel, Google Suite, Trello, JavaScript, jQuery, Linux, Microsoft SQL Server, SQL, Microsoft Word, Adobe Photoshop

EDUCATION

IT: Programming
NSCC IT Campus, Halifax, NS

September 2018 – May 2020

High School Diploma

September 2014 – June 2015

Prince Andrew High School, Dartmouth, NS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Developer

May 2022 - June 2022

Current Studios, Halifax, NS

- Worked with a team of front end and black end developers, QA and managers.
- Completed learning project of Node JS, and React JS.
- Scrum methodology

Dishwasher/Prep Cook

June 2021 – May 2022

Finbar's Portland Hills, Dartmouth, NS

- Working quickly to clean dishes and cooking equipment.
- Preparing food and ingredients to be used during service.
- Resupplying the kitchen when needed.
- Follow best safety practices and maintain a clean and safe work environment.

Senior Developer

November 2019 - March 2020

Nova Scotia Community College, Halifax, NS

- Lead team of 7 junior developers in handling various development tasks in support of IT Job Fair
- Front-end and back-end development in Laravel Framework
- Maintaining a Project Board on Trello and Github
- Website: itjobfair.ca

Junior Developer

April 2019 - May 2019

Nova Scotia Community College, Halifax, NS

As a junior developer, I assisted in developing an online trading card game. My role focused on developing the home page, Player's page, as well as incorporating responsive design into the site. This involved using HTML and CSS to create the website. The team used GitHub to assign tasks.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Team Coordinator

September 2019 - March 2020

NSCC IT Job Fair & Conference- 2020, Dartmouth, NS

Responsible for helping managed the team by tracking team minutes, participating in meetings, being a part of the leadership group and helping track loose ends.

IT Technician May 2017 - Present

Dartmouth Learning Network, Dartmouth, NS

- Diagnose computer problems, monitor computer processing systems, install software and perform tests on computer equipment and programs.
- Set up computer equipment, schedule maintenance and teach clients to use programs.
- Perform computer repairs and computer parts ordering.
- Maintain an inventory of over 40 computers.

MAMBEC Senior Instructor

March 2014 - June 2015

Martial Art Mind-Body Education Centre (MAMBEC), Dartmouth, NS

- Trained children in Martial Arts and self-discipline.
- Worked year-round on weekends, school professional development days and summer vacation.
- Completed over 500 Leadership/Volunteer hours.

PROJECTS

Vex Monsters

December 2019 - Present

- Vex Monsters is a fantasy platform game, where you save monsters from an evil mysterious villain.
- Team Leader
- Programming the logic and User Interface of the game from moving the player, AI, dialogue, NPC, and other game mechanics.
- Story Writer for the backstory
- Maintaining a Project Board on Trello
- Conduct weekly Scrums

ADDITIONAL TRAINING & ACHIEVEMENTS

Challenge NS 2017 Second Place MAMBEC Martial Art Black Bel

2017

2012